wa alaikum wa rahmatullah wa barakatuhu wa asalamu alaykum
Alhamdulillah
wa chadu anna Muhammadan abduhu wa rasuluhu
our last discussions have been about a group of people
They depend and become deceived that Allah has provided them extensive favours in this
in fact their wives and children are made to be successful in the matters of this
dunya so they become deceived that their comfort and the luxury that they enjoy
that is all that matters irrespective of their dispositions towards the laws of Allah
regarding that they don't care they think that as long as they have comfort and luxury
they have everything you can say they want then what else is life?
Life is about material comfort you want to buy something you can buy
you want to order for something you can order you want to eat something you can eat it
you want to buy whatever you want to buy you are capable of buying it
they give it various names you can pay your bills and that's all that matters
This individual may be dealing with a riba
This individual may be a yahoo boy
May Allah protect us
This individual may be dealing with drugs that the governments of countries have prohibited
He may go on and on he may be involved in banditry
He may be involved in kidnapping, arm robbery
All of these evils and those that may even be worse than it
as a political office seeker or holder they don't care to kill people
and execute them, take their lives
All that matters to them as far as they are concerned is that they can obtain luxury
They can obtain comfort
They can get whatever they want from this dunya
For these kinds of people
All the reminders they will hear from the lessons on the days of Jum'ah
in khutbah, in various lessons that they attend
They set all those things aside
They will even tell you that the summons will bring you back in life
They will draw you back, they will set you back
So they set aside the lessons
They set aside the laws of Allah
They set aside the Quran and its restrictions
And they set aside the hadith, the sunnah and its prohibitions
Allah said
When they had set aside all of these things
that have come to them from their Lord
He said
When they set aside the laws of Allah
and the Deen of Allah
We opened up unto them the doors of everything they want
Everything they wanted, they could get it
They got money, in fact they even have sound health
They may even be handsome and beautiful
They have good skins, palatial homes
Huge cars of comfort and luxury
In fact, they may own private jets, private ship, private this, private that
They set aside, they forgot all of what the reminders that have come to them
We also, we open the doors of all comfort and luxury
That they were in that luxury and comfort
Until
When they begin to gloat, when they begin to gladiate
When they begin to delight, enjoy
They are so happy about the lifestyle that they live
Allah said
When they enjoyed, they delighted, they were happy
They'd forgotten that Allah has instructed them
and they have violated the injunctions of Allah
They think that life can go on as they want
in their own comfort and luxury
When they begin to enjoy and delight
Becoming happy with all of what we have done to them
Allah said
That is when we catch them
We catch them so suddenly
And they did talk on to become from the losers
The Prophet ﷺ
He gave a statement that explains this further
ﷺ
He said
You will see
The individual will be upon various kinds of acts of unrighteousness
Sinfulness to acquire worlds
The man does not care, all that matters is the money
If you find Allah
You will see
Allah was providing him all that he wanted from the things
and the comfort of this dunya and its luxury
Just
Just as that servant likes it
The Prophet said
Let it be clear, that is nothing except his tidraj
Is a gradual approach to get him caught up
In the punishment of Allah
He is gradually being wrapped up
The punishment will soon wrap him up
For he is made to forget
He is given the chance to forget that he will be caught up one day
So that explains that verse we read
When Allah said
When they forget what they have been reminded of
We will open for them the gates of everything
So that when they rejoice in what they have been given
They will take what they have been given
So that they will be blessed
We beg Allah to protect us all
Brothers
When you get everything you want on sinfulness
You are up on a river
You are up on yahu
You make ritual killings to gain wealth
You steal the money belonging to government
You are a court judge
You collect money to judge unlawfully
All that matters is who is able to pay you the highest
As if justice is for the highest leader
As a classroom teacher
You go on with exam malpractice
As long as the parents of the students can pay you money
You encourage and support exam malpractices
And you collect the money from that
Thinking that whatever you gain from it is comfort and luxury
The prophet said
Is a gradual catch
Allah is gradually pushing you to your place of disgrace
To your place of punishment
May Allah protect all of us
Some of the people went so deep in that thinking
Thinking that all that matters is money
You see them they begin to coin expressions to support what they do
Ibn al-Qayyim told us two of those expressions and he refuted them
One of those expressions is that they will say
Ad-dunya naqdun wal-akhiratu nasi'a
Wal-naqdu anfa'u minal nasi'a
Fa ana la abi'u naqdan
La abi'u naqdan
Fa ana la abi'u naqdan bi nasi'a
Ibn al-Qayyim said
These people who don't care about the worlds that they make and how they make the wealth
These people who all that matters to them is the present comfort and luxury that they enjoy
Irrespective of the lawlessness that that involves
You hear them saying that Ad-dunya naqdun
This world is cashed down
Worldly affairs is cashed down
Once you do kidnapping they give you cash
And this is what the kidnappers and the banditry
This is what they spread, be themselves on the social media
May Allah protect all of us
The money is cash, cashed down
Wal-akhiratu nasi'a
If you say you want to be patient
Til akhirah
Observing Salat and avoiding prohibitions
That one is foul
You only get down one liter, liter is foul
Wal-naqdu anfa'u minal nasi'a
And what you get now, now, now, now
It is more beneficial than what you are promised in the future
Fa ana la abi'u naqdan bi nasi'a
I will not leave, I will not transact something
That I can get now, now, now
I will not leave it, hoping to get it tomorrow
No, I want it now
Al-Imam ibn al-Qayyim refuted this as we read in class last week
He said, Rahimahullah
Wa qulu hadha l-qa'il
The statement of this person
Saying that
Al dunya naqdan wal-akhiratu nasi'a
Dis qa'il
Qulu hadha l-qa'ili
This statement of this person who has forgotten himself
Inside unlawful acquisition of worlds
You robbed this one
You kidnapped that one
You stole that one
You boggled the other one
This is all that you enjoy thinking that you have comfort and luxury
You cheated that one
You abused that one
You killed this one
In all of these you think you are enjoying luxury and comfort
Thinking that, yes, it is here
Now, now, now
If you say you want to wait till akhirah
You want to wait till hereafter
Hereafter is fa'u
This person is saying this
Fa'u
Ibn al-Qa'im said, Rahimahullah
Yes, it is true
If what you want to get in the immediate
And what you plan to get in the future
The immediate collection
When nasi'a, the one you want to collect later
If they are the same
No problem
You want to get 10,000 naira today
Two weeks time you get the 10,000
They are the same, no problem
In that case you can argue that
What you get immediately is better than what you get later
So if what you are saying is that
You will get 10,000 naira now
And hereafter on the day of Qiyamah
When you abstain from sin
It is that same 10,000 naira of this dunya that Allah will give you
Then your statement may be correct
So if what you want to collect in the immediate
And what you will collect in the future
If they are the same
You can say what you are saying
It is better to collect it immediately
But if they are different
If in the immediate
You would collect 10,000 naira for example
And in one year's time of the same transaction
You will collect one million
You will collect one billion
He said
Then collecting it later is better and much more
It is better
And more advantageous
So if your argument to be correct
That you want this dunya, dunya, dunya
As for live sins, live this, allow reward
That one is later
And you want to collect it now is better than later
To sin to collect it now is better than abstinence from sin
And get sin rewarded later
This your argument to be correct
If what you want to collect in the immediate
And the one you want to collect in the future
If they are the same
Then that you collect it in the immediate is better
But if they are different
And what you will collect in the future
Is much more in its quantity
And much more better in its quality
Then collecting it later is more advantageous
And definitely better
How then will it be
When the situation is that
The entirety of this dunya
From the first day of creation
To the last day of creation
From the best sin of luxury and comfort
To all of them put together
It does not equate a single breath
Compared to the breath
Compared to the goodies of akhirah
The whole dunya
All of it put together
It does not equate the smallest breath in the akhirah
It does not equate the smallest speck of dust
If there are dusts
But for want of expression
The entirety of this dunya does not equate
The weight of the smallest speck in akhirah
Just as it occurs in the hadith
Collected by Imam Ahmad
And what Tirmidhi
From the hadith of Mostauri
Who said
The messenger of Allah said
What is the worth of this dunya
If you compare it to akhirah
Accept us
Any one of you
Will insert his finger
Inside the ocean
Let him see what is it that
That finger will bring out from water
The comparison, the illustration of the vast difference
Between the joy
Between the comfort
Between the luxury of this dunya
And the joy and the luxury of the goodness
And all of these of akhirah
Is that place one finger into the water
To the ocean
Atlantic, Pacific
Place one finger into it
Remove the finger
Can you compare the quantity of water on your hands
To the quantity of water in the ocean
That is the similarity
That is how small this dunya is
Compared to akhirah
So he said
If this is the comparison
Of this dunya
In its entirety from its first day
And including all of its luxury and comfort
The comparison to the akhirah is the comparison of
The illustration of dipping one single finger into water
Bringing it out
So all the dunya is that water on the finger
And the akhirah is the water of the ocean
Are they comparable?
The whole dunya from day one
Five billion years, ten billion years
Whatever the billion years
And all the enjoyment of the dunya
Compared to the akhirah
Is like the water on a finger
Compared to the water of an ocean
He said
The necessity of the akhirah
If this is the case with the entirety of this dunya
How then, what is the extent
Of a person's fifty, sixty years
That you spent in this dunya
Compared to the akhirah
Give the whole of dunya
One thousand years, fifty thousand years
One hundred thousand years, two hundred thousand years of this dunya
And all the enjoyment in it
The enjoyment in Paris, in Madrid, in Washington
In Brazil, in the UK
Government house, UAE
You own everything
From day one of this dunya
To the last day of this dunya
What that compares with regards to the akhirah is
Water on a single finger
Compared to water in the ocean
How about just your own fifty, twenty, seventy years
From Amik Daru
Or more really Ensa
What then is the extent of the age of an individual
In this world
The nisbatil el akhirah
Compared to the length of time
What is the comparison of that your own small enjoyment
Within that fifty, sixty, seventy, eighty
One hundred years that you spent in this dunya
Take it that it was all upon an enjoyment
Compare the length of time
And the quality of delight and comfort
It is just like putting one hand in the finger
In the ocean
Compared to the entire ocean
That is the whole dunya
So what is the size of your own hundred years
You will see that it is infinitesimal
Which of them both will be preferred by somebody who is intelligent
Which one is preferable to the person who is intelligent
Is it giving preference to this agile
This quick passing one
This thing that goes, that passes away so easily and quickly
Is it giving it preference
This quick passing dunya
Within this small period of hundred years or two hundred years that you spent
And then losing out in the continuous enjoyment
The enjoyment of akhirah
Which one will you choose
Will you choose that small enjoyment and comfort of this dunya for hundred years
And then you lose out
You throw away continuous and everlasting enjoyment in akhirah
Which one will you choose
That small one in this dunya
That small yacht you are riding
That small private jet you are riding
That small house you built in whether banana or orange or apple island
Or you built it in Baytama and Asukuru
Or you built it in France, in Paris, in Argentina, in Switzerland
You stole the money to do it
The whole of that comfort is still small
The whole of that luxury is still small
When you compare it to the luxury of akhirah
So which one will you prefer
That small one
Throwing away al-khairi daim
Throwing away the one that is everlasting
The small one that will leave you in few years
If you do yahoo and kill somebody to get money
For how long will you spend that money
If you took drugs to get money
For how long will you spend it
If you perverted justice as a George to get money
If you are placed in charge of pension funds and you stole their money
For how long will you spend it
How long, 50 years, 100 years
Is it sensible to give preference to this
And then you lose al-khairi daim
The everlasting peace and joy and comfort of the akhirah
Is it sensible
Which one is sensible there
Am tarqushay in haqqir
Or that for you to live
To be patient regarding the prohibition of ariba
To be patient regarding the prohibition of banditry and kidnapping
To be patient regarding not killing people in political office
You are patient regarding that
Let me leave it if it involves haram
Is this one
Is this better for you to leave something that is haqqir, despicable
It is even small
It will leave you in a very short time
This is the enjoyment of this dunya
That is the comfort, that is your haqq, your yatch, your private jet
They are haqqir, sagir, munkathein and qarib
They are despicable
They are small things, they are sagir
They are munkathein and qarib
They will become disconnected from you in a very short time
Is there anybody who has enjoyed riding a yatch
Or a private jet in 70, 80 years
It is munkathein and a very small time now they will leave you
Is this one better, is it better for you to sacrifice this one
Why I don't want to eat riba
Why I cannot involve in kidnapping
Why I cannot involve in banditry
I cannot steal government money
Is this one better for you
You left all of these
Because you want to get
What is so, so valuable
That the valuable, the value cannot be quantified
It has no equivalent
The comfort of akhirah has no equivalent
It's so, so valuable without equivalent
The quantity does not have a number
Here in this dunya you can have more than 10 private jets
Okay, half 20
In akhirah the things of comfort and luxury do not have numbers
The time you will spend enjoying them
It does not have a limit
Likewise the length of these value
Enjoyment, advantage, happiness, delight, comfort, luxury of akhirah
They have no equivalent
Their numbers does not have an end
They are infinite
The time with which you enjoy them
It does not have any end
The extent of the enjoyment
It does not have a limit nor a restriction
So which one is better
The one you collect in akhirah by being patient in this world
Or the one you collect hastily in this world that is small
That is haqir
That is despicable
That is sagir, small
That will become disconnected from you in a very short time
When you die
Is it this one you prefer
Or the one that has no over, no limits
Comfort without limits
Luxury without restrictions
Which one will you prefer
For a time that is limitless
Which one will you prefer if you are reasonable
May Allah protect all of us
So for somebody to say that irrespective of how he earns the money
All that matters is luxury
And comfort after all
This dunya is cashed down, akhirah is later
I can't wait to do that later
Are you being reasonable with that statement
Or you are being stupid with it
May Allah protect us from being unreasonable
The one who is reasonable amongst us
The one who picks
The one who picks an everlasting comfort and luxury
That has no limits
Its numbers have no limits
The time, the time, the time you spend enjoying
They have no limits, no restrictions
The length and the vastness of the joy and the light
They have no limits
So a Nasiah hair cannot be compared to the knackered
Collecting its later hair
What you want to collect you can compare it
To the small disgusting thing you want to get in this dunya
That you are calling comfort
That thing that made you got into haram
Carelessly and audaciously
If you are sensible you will not do that
May Allah protect all of us
There is a second thinking Ibn al-Qayyim sought to also explain
And refute
He said
As for the statement of the second person who says
I will not leave something that is certain
Because of something that I am not even sure I can get
Why are you not sure?
How does akhira become something that has doubts
You are doubting what? You are doubting akhira
So he begins to say oh this dunya is something I can see
I can see it
I can have it now
As for akhira
So he begins to say that
The enjoyment of this dunya, the luxury and the comfort
They are something that you can see now, now, now
As for the comfort and the luxury of akhira
He calls it
Something about which you are not sure
It is doubtful
That is what this person thinks
May Allah protect us
So because he thinks that the enjoyment of akhira is doubtful
He begins to relish in sins and evil
And anyhow collects the wealth
Just gets the wealth
Just gets money
My brother all that matters is money, comforts
I can't trade this for anything
Okay
Ibn al-Qayyim said
This kind of a person it will be said to him
You who say that the enjoyment of this dunya they are certain
As for akhira it is
We are not sure
Which kind of akhira are you talking about
This one that we are seeing that is a reality
Listen
Your problem is that you are either
The reality is that
You are either upon a doubt regarding the promises of Allah
You are doubting those promises
You are either doubtful
About the promises of Allah
And the threats that he gave
He promised al-jannah
He also threatened about jahannam
You are not sure
You are about ease and doubt
You are either in doubt
About the things that his books
Taurat, injil, zubur, quran
All of these books
What they came with
And the prophets and the messengers that he had sent
You are either doubting all of these
Or you are upon certainty
We want to lay the foundation for that refutation
Someone who says this dunya is certain but akhira is uncertain
You are either doubtful regarding these things
You are doubting al-jannah
You are doubting jahannam
You are doubting the contents
Inside the books that were sent down by Allah
And the statements and the promises and caution and warnings
Of his rosul
Or that you are certain about them
So let's take case one and two
If you are certain about those promises
And those threats
In the quran
In the books before the quran
And those in the sunnah
If you are upon certainty
You are certain that these things are true
Don't worry
What you have left of riba
What you have left of sin
Of kidnapping
Of banditry
Of yahoo yahoo
Of stealing government money to make money
Of stealing and killing to end political offices
All of these things they are
They are small things
They have small time
Small things of small times
They are despicable
Easily they will become disconnected from you
They don't last
And curbing over a short time
They will go away
You left them
The arm ring
For something
Something that is war
There is no doubt inside it
And it does not stop
It does not have an end
So if you leave riba my dear brother
If you leave a transaction that is haram
My dear brother
If you avoid and stay away from banditry
From kidnapping
From stealing government money
If you keep away from all of these things
You have iman and yaqeen
About the day of qiyam
About the promises of Allah
About the contents of the Quran
About the contents of the sunnah
About the promises
You believe in them
That all these things are things of reality
No problem
Don't worry
All of what you have left
All these unlawful means to wealth
That you have abandoned
They are small
They are agila
They are transient
They are despicable
They become disconnected
They go away easily
And curbing over a little time
This is what you have left
So you have not lost
You left them for something else
For something that is certain
The rewards of the year after
Al-jannah is certain
The jannah is certain
The na'im of al-jannah is certain
The promises of Allah are real
And these things
There is no doubt about it
Al-jannah has no end
Anyone who gets into al-jannah
Remains in it forever
So he said
Case two
If your case is that
You are really, really doubtful
About the promises of Allah
About the threats of Allah
About jannah
About
What the books that Allah sent down
What they said about year after
You are actually in doubt about
What the messengers have told us about year after
If you are in doubt about these matters
Then we don't have any discussion with you
You are a kafir
Anyone who doubts the year after is a kafir
Anyone who doubts the promises of Allah is a kafir
The one who doubts the year after is a kafir
The one who doubts the books of Allah that he sent down
The one who doubts them is kafir
The one who doubts the anbiya and the rusul is kafir
If you are in doubt about Allah
About his books
About his rusul, his messengers
You have doubts over them
There is nothing we want to start telling you if you are a kafir
Go back and study iman
Study fiqh, study the foundations of iman
Go back and study the verses of the Quran
That clearly evidence Allah's being
And his absolute power
And his absolute will
And his oneness
Go back to the Quran
If you are in doubt about Allah
You are in doubt about his books
You are in doubt about his messengers
Such a person is a kafir
If you now say you want this dunya anyhow
You want to get money anyhow
Your problem is not that dunya first
The first problem you have is iman
Go back to study iman
Go back and study the verses of the Quran
That points and evidence the fact that there is Allah
That points and evidence the fact of Allah's absolute power
And his will
The verses that points to his oneness
Go back and study those verses of the Quran
That point to the truthfulness of his prophets
The truthfulness
The truthfulness of his books that he has sent to his messengers
Regarding what they have said about Allah
And about the day of Qiyamah
Do not be deceived with this dunya
Do not be deceived by evil companions that you have
Do not be deceived by desires that are temporary
Don't let them deceive you
Those things that have carried you
To begin to doubt the promises of Allah in the hereafter
Do not get deceived by the comfort of this dunya
Do not get deceived by evil companions, evil friends,
Evil relatives, evil wife, evil daughter, evil son
They make you feel deceived about this dunya
Regarding Allah
And then you begin to doubt
You begin to doubt the truth and the certainty of the promises of Allah in the hereafter
Do not let those temporary desires that you are able to fulfill
Do not let them deceive you
Unfortunately those were the things that made you begin to doubt the promises of Allah
O mankind, O human being doubting, stand up, be ready
Go and study about Allah
Go and examine the evidences in the books regarding Allah
Study them, examine them, contemplate them
Until it will become clear to you
So Tajarrad, stand up
Be ready, come alone, Tajarrad, be independent minded
Stand up and then study, examine, contemplate regarding Allah
Go back to the Quran, pay attention to it, study it, contemplate the evidences
So that it will be clear to you that
The message that the messengers have brought regarding Allah
That is the truth about which there is no doubt
It is an everlasting truth
It is not the truth that is true in some certain circumstances
That will be found to be a lie in other circumstances
And that when you study this book, the Quran, the Sunnah
You contemplate it, you examine its evidences
It will also be clear to you that
The creator of this universe
And the creator of the end
He is far exalted
He is far purified
He is far away from imperfections
He is far away exalted
He is far away purified and holy and sanctified
He is far away glorified
Away from imperfections
A way Allah is far away
Allah is exalted away from everything that contradicts what his books that he has sent
And the messengers that he has sent, what they tell us
That is whatever contradicts what the Quran
And the books that have come down before it
Whatever contradicts it
Likewise the messengers what they have taught
The things that contradict them regarding Allah
They are not true, Allah is far away from that
Allah is exalted as he has been described by his messengers
And the books they have come with
Anything other than that
Allah is far away from it
Allah is exalted away from all those things
Subhanahu wa Ta'ala
So if you learn the Quran
If you study the Quran
If you examine the verses
If you pay attention
It will be clear to you that what the messengers have brought
Regarding Allah
That is the absolute truth
That has no doubt at all
It is an absolute truth that is true in every circumstance
Not true in some circumstances
And inappropriate in other circumstances, no
It will also be clear to you when you study the Quran properly
That the creator of the entirety of this Universe
Like the Lord of all the Heavens and the Earth
Subhanahu wa Ta'ala
Allah is far exalted
Is far purified and
Subhanahu wa Ta'ala
Far from all the imperfections that people will describe him
These things that are
Anything people say that contradicts what the books
And what the messengers say
It Allah is far away from them
Anyone who ascribes Allah to any other than what
The books and the messengers have described him with
Such a person has insulted Allah
Subhanahu wa Ta'ala
Such a person has rejected Allah
Calling him Allah
Subhanahu wa Ta'ala
If you describe Allah
If you ascribe to Allah any other than what
The messengers and the books have called him
Subhanahu wa Ta'ala
That's a person
Is rejecting and denying
Allah's Lordship
Subhanahu wa Ta'ala
And his sovereignty
Because
From the things that are absolutely impossible
With anyone that still has
Sound natural instincts
From the things that is impossible is that
It should be clear to us
That
The one who is absolutely the true king and sovereign
Whose power and authority is clear to all
He is now unable
Our ignorant
He does not know anything
He does not hear
He does not speak
He does not command
Neither does he prohibit
He does not reward
Neither does he punish
He cannot empower
He cannot honor
Whomever he wills
He cannot disgrace whom he wills
He cannot even send his messengers
To the various far distant areas in his kingdom
And his various regions
While he does not pay attention to the condition of those under him
Rather he left them just like that
No responsibilities, no duties
He abandons them without attention
And without care
This is not sensible
It is not sensible at all
It is not sensible
And these are things people bring regarding Allah
If they have not learnt about Allah
And accepted regarding Allah
From the books of the messengers of Allah
That they came with them
If you reject the Quran
If you reject the Sunnah
If you reject the messengers of Allah
These are the things you'll be thinking about Allah
That Allah does not speak
He does not talk
He does not have control
These issues we are discussing
Ikwa, don't forget
In all of these
Ibn al-Qayyim is refuting the one who has doubts about Akhira
The one who says that the Akhira
Is something of doubt
Ibn al-Qayyim is saying that
Is it that you are doubting the promises of Allah al-Jannah
You are doubting Jahannam
You are doubting all of what is contained in the books
In the Quran, in the books before it
You are doubting what the prophets of Allah have brought
If your case is that you actually believe in them
You are just making this statement
Or that you believe in these things truly
And you abandoned Haram because of these things
No problem, you have succeeded
What you have left of this dunya is small
Akhira is really certain
Without any kind of doubt
No stoppage and end
But if it is the individual that doubts
He is truly in doubt about Allah
He is in doubt about the books
He is in doubt about the messengers
His own case is that
He should be directed to study Iman afresh
You don't believe in Allah
If you are in doubt about these matters
So go back to the basics of Iman
Go back to the foundations, the verses of the Quran
These verses point to Allah's being
And his power
And his will absolutely
And the oneness of Allah
And the truth, the reality of the books that he has sent
And the truth in the message that has been conveyed by his messengers
Regarding Allah swt
And the day of judgment
So if you are in doubt, truly in doubt about Allah
Truly in doubt about the reality of recompense and Akhira
Go back to the Quran
Go back to the Quran, don't be deceived by people talking
Saying that they are attested the hadith that
Or the comfort you have
Don't be deceived by it
Don't be deceived by evil friends
Telling you not to believe in Allah
Telling you what is the truth
This Jannah, this Jannah, they are just promising us there is nothing about that
Don't be deceived by them
Don't be deceived by these temporary things you are enjoying today
These things are the things that make you begin to doubt Allah
You have money, you have wealth, you think that you are sensible
Everything is smooth for you
So you are doubting Allah
You are doubting the day of Qiyam
Please stand up
Please be independent minded
Go back and begin to study about Allah
Examine the evidences in the Quran
So study the Quran, study the verses until
So that it can become clear to you that what the Prophets have brought
That is the truth
There is no shak regarding it
And there is no inqita
It is not a truth that is true in some circumstances
And not true in some circumstances
They are absolute truths
Sustainable truths in every situation
If you study the Quran well
Contemplate its evidences and examine it
It will be clear to you that the one who has created this world
And the heavens and the earth is their Lord
Is far exalted
Is far purified
Is far away from every kind of imperfection
Regarding the things that people who ask
Giving themselves ideas
Atheists, semi-theists, theists, theists
Are lies far from all of those things that they are talking about
I hope that this lesson is clear
Two major points
This world, people say it is nakdu
They can't wait for nasir
It is cashed down
They can't wait to get the rewards of a year after
Tell them that this cashed down you are talking about
If it has a value that is equivalent to the one you are waiting for
Then you are waiting
Collecting it in cash is better
But if they are not comparable at all
Then the reasonable thing is to wait
The comparison of this dunya to akhirah is like a man putting a finger in the ocean
What is the comparison of water on your hand to the vast ocean?
You can't even say you have water on your hand
That is the comparison between dunya and akhirah
Akhira is vast
So if you can wait to collect that one that is vast
Is that not reasonable?
Is there any reasonable person who wants to collect a handful of water
And throw away water off an ocean?
You wait to collect the ocean if you are sensible
So be patient regarding riba
Be patient regarding business transactions that are unlawful
Be patient so that you end things bigger and better
Wider and more everlasting than all of that in akhirah
This is point one
Point two the one who says that
The enjoyment of this dunya they are real and certain
As for akhirah is not certain about it is end out
We say if you just made this statement
If you are truly certain about akhirah
You are a person of iman
Be assured that what you left from unlawful transactions in this dunya
They are small
They are small things compared to akhirah
But if it is really true that you are in doubt about akhirah
You need to go back to study the Quran
Because this is your condition is the condition of kufr
Doubting Allah
Doubting akhirah
Doubting the contents of the Quran
Doubting the message of the messengers
It is kufr, disbelief in Allah
So go back to the Quran to study it properly
Go back to the Quran to examine it properly
It will be clear to you
That Allah has created this universe
All what the messengers told us in the books
That they have brought their truth
We will continue with this explanation in the subsequent class
A lot of people are battling with this now
They read so many things from the social media
And they become beguiled
They begin to doubt iman
They begin to doubt Allah
They begin to doubt the day of qiyam
Please go back to the Quran
Be it in Allah
We come back to these issues in the subsequent class
About Brahman
We have a few questions quickly
The first question here is
Is there a limit to what a fashion designer can
Sew for females
For instance, making a stylish dress for someone
Who doesn't wear a himal to combine
There is a limit to what a female fashion designer can
Sew for females
Making a stylish dress
If you know that
That person you are making that dress for
Wear it like that publicly
Don't make it for them
You know one kafirah will wear that cloth publicly
Like that
Don't make it
If you know that
Irrespective of how flashy an attractive dress may be
And showing her bodies
You know that she will not wear it like that in public
She will only wear it like that before her husband
Then it is lawful
I hope that it is clear
If you know that
Those cloths the kafirah will wear
It will show from her neck
To her legs
It will expose her indecently
We know how they dress
If you know that this is how she will wear it outside
In fact
She wants to wear it like that to cause trouble and fitna
Please don't do it for her
Reject it
The money you have rejected
Allah will bring you something better than that in the hereafter
But if you know that irrespective no matter how also
White or expository the cloth is
She is a muslima
She will only wear it in front of her husband
Then you can make it
I hope that it is clear
About the law
We are sure that we will love you
Ameen
There is a question here
Which one is greater?
Is it to be tried in the aspects of savity towards Allah?
Or to be tried in the aspects of the ones you matters?
Iqwa from the dua of the prophet Muhammad
Sallallahu alaihi wa sallam
Is that Allah should not place our trial
Wala tajjal musibatana fi dinina
The trial should not come in our religion O brothers
May Allah protect all of us
Aman has been upon Tawheed
And then now he begins to tie something on his hand
On his waist seeking protection from those things
This is a big trial
Because that trial is regarding his din
A woman has been mustaqima
She now begins to desire a man for sinna
This is a trial in your din
May Allah protect all of us
And we have heard and seen things like this
A woman under her husband
Her loyalty is under another man
Who is attracted to Allah wa alam
These kinds of things are fitan
A man married to a wife 2, 3, 4
Still desire us of sinna
From other women
A man that Allah has blessed
With the knowledge of the din
He abandons it
He faces the knowledge of this din
He had become ignorant about the religion
He had memorized the Quran
He abandons it
He runs into other things
These are trials regarding the din
May Allah protect all of us
As for trials in the matters of dunya
He had money before he did not have a gain
He had a car before he did not have a gain
We don't like it too
They are trials too
But they are not like
The trials that has afflicted the din of a person
Whatever afflicts the din of an individual
Has afflicted his heir after
So it is certainly worse
It's certainly worse
May Allah protect all of us
From the trials of this dunya and the akhirah
Keep us firm, Ya Rabb al-Alam
Protect us, strengthen us
Forgive us, Ya Rabb al-Alam
Pardon our mistakes
Keep us steadfast upon your din
Ya Dhul-Jalali wal-Ikram
Allahumma salli ala Muhammadin wa ala ali Muhammadin
Kama sallaita ala Ibrahim wa ala ali Ibrahim
Innaka hamidu majid
Allahumma barika ala Muhammadin wa ala ali Muhammadin
Kama baraqta ala Ibrahim wa ala ali Ibrahim
Innaka hamidu majid
Subhanaka Allah al-Muhammadan
Al-Wa La Ilaha Illa Allah
Astagfirullah Al-Fatiha
Assalamu alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu
Wa alaikum wa salam wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu
Wa alaikum wa rahmatullahi wa barakatuhu